m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
Now you take it easy, slugger.
Joey!
Joe Doyle!
All right! What do you want?
I got one of your birds.
I recognised him by the band.
It must be Danny-boy. I lost him in the last race.
He flew into my coop.
-You want him? -I got to watch myself these days.
You know what I mean?
Don't worry.
-I'll take him up to your loft. -Okay, I'll see you on the roof.
How goes?
He's up on the roof.
The pigeon?
Yeah, it worked.
I think somebody fell off the roof.
He thought he'd sing to the Crime Commission. He won't.
I thought they'd talk to him.
That's the idea.
I thought they'd talk to him and get him to dummy up.
Maybe he gave them an argument.
I figured the worst they was gonna do was lean on him a little bit.
He's been giving Johnny the Boss a lot of arguments lately.
He wasn't a bad kid, that Joey.
A canary.
Maybe he could sing, but he couldn't fly.
Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
I'll be in there later and....
Father Barry is here.
Same thing happened to my Andy five years ago.
-You're the boy's father? -That's right.
Looks like he fell off the roof, or maybe he was pushed.
-Any ideas? -No.
He was the only longshoreman that had the guts to talk to the crime investigators.
-Who asked you? -Everybody knows that.
Shut up.
-lf he took my advice he wouldn't be---Everyone knows that.
I said, "Shut up!"
I know how you feel about cops, but if you give me...
some leads I could
I kept telling him, "Don't say nothing.
"Keep quiet, you'll live longer."
I've been on the docks all my life, boy, and there's one thing I learned.
You don't ask no questions, you don't answer no questions...
unless you want to wind up like that.
Edie, come here.
I want to talk to you.
Father, who'd want to kill Joey?
Stay away from him! Stay away from him!
Edie, listen!
Remember time and faith are great healers.
Father, my brother is dead and you talk about time and faith.
My brother was the best kid in the neighbourhood and everybody said so.
I'm in the church if you need me.
You're in the church if I need you?
Did you ever hear of a saint hiding in a church?
I want to know who killed my brother!
What's the matter with you, punk?
Boss, Packy wants another drink on the cuff.
Give it to him.
And here's the cut on the shape-up.
891 men, $3 a head. That's $2,673.
Charley, you count them.
The banana boat is 46 tomorrow.
If we pull a walkout, it might be a few bucks from the shippers.
-Them bananas go bad in a hurry. -Ask $2,000.
Clowns can't fight.
There's nobody tough anymore.
Hi, slugger.
Hi, kid.
Where's Morgan? Where's that big banker of mine?
Right here, Mr. Friendly.
-Hi, JP, how's business? -Having trouble with Kelly again, boss.
He won't take no loans and Big Mac puts him to work anyway.
-He's my wife's nephew. -He won't take no loans!
I got to put him to work. She'd murder me!
That's why I never got married.
Here's the interest on the day, boss. $532.
You count it.
Counting makes me sleepy.
You handle that sheet metal all right?
It was easy. The new checker faked the receipt. Here.
You want to talk to me, take the cigar out of your mouth.
-Stow the receipt. I'll take the cash. -Sure.
-Here you are, 45 bills. -Terry, you count this.
Come on, go on, it's good for you.
-lt develops your mind. -What mind?
Shut up. I like the kid.
Remember the night he took Farella at St. Nick's, Charley?
We won a bundle. Real tough. A big try.
I lost the count.
Okay, forget it, Einstein.
How come you never got an education like your brother Charley?
The only arithmetic he ever got was hearing the referee count up to 10.
You're not too funny today, Fat Man.
Hey, what gives with our boy tonight, Charley?
He isn't himself.
It's the Joey Doyle thing and how he exaggerates the thing.
Too much Marquis of Queensbury softens him up.
Listen, I'm a soft touch, too. Ask any rummy on the dock...
if I'm not good for a fin any time they put the arm on me.
But my old lady raised us 10 kids on a stinking watchman's pension.
When I was 16, I had to beg for work in the hold.
I didn't work my way up out of there for nothing.
I know that, Johnny, I know it.
Taking over this local took a little doing.
There were rough fellas in the way. They gave me this to remember them by.
He kept his hand over his throat to stay alive and he still went after them.
I know what's eating you.
I got 2,000 dues-paying members in this local, that's $72,000 a year legitimate.
When each one of them puts in a couple of bucks a day just to make sure...
the work's steady, well, figure it out.
That's just for openers.
We've got the fattest piers in the fattest harbour in the world.
Everything moves in and out, we take our cut.
Why shouldn't we? If we can get it, we're entitled to it.
You don't suppose I can afford to be boxed out of a deal like this, do you?
A deal I sweated and bled for, on account of one lousy little cheese-eater...
that Doyle bum, who thinks he can squeal to the crime commission. Do you?
Do you?
No, Johnny. I just figured I should have been told.
I make it $2,623.
You're $50 short, Skins.
Gimme.
-I must've miscounted. -Gimme!
You come from Green Point, go back there. You don't work here no more.
Here, kid, here's half a bill. Go get you a load on.
No, I'm okay, Johnny, thanks.
Present from your Uncle Johnny.
And Mac, tomorrow morning when you shape the men, put Terry up in the loft.
Number one. Every day.
It's nice, easy work if you check in and goof off on a coffee bag.
Okay?
You got a real friend here.
Now don't forget it.
Why should he forget it?
Thanks, Johnny.
All right, payday.
Rony.
Mac.
Hi, Terry.
-Hi, kid. -I was just going to feed them.
I already fed them.
You must've been up early?
I was up anyhow, so I figured I might as well.
They sure got it made.
Eating, sleeping, flying around like crazy, raising gobs of squabs.
Well, I better get over there.
Be careful. Don't spill no water on the floor. I don't want them to catch cold.
I'll see you around.
Come on, Tony, give me the tabs.
He was a good boy, that Doyle kid.
Sure he was, that's why he got it in the head.
But he couldn't learn to keep his mouth shut.
Hey, Pop, why don't you go home?
The boys at work today will be chipping in gladly.
No thanks, fellas, I'm gonna shape.
Who do you think'll pay for the funeral?
Johnny Friendly, the "great labour leader."
Why don't you keep that big mouth of yours shut?
What are you, a wise guy?
If I was wise, I wouldn't be no longshoreman for 30 years.
I'm poorer now than when I started.
-Wise guy. -Big mouth.
Don't mess with those guys.
I brought you Joey's windbreaker. It might come in handy.
-Go ahead, wear it. -Thanks, Pop.
Mine's more full of holes than the Pittsburgh infield.
Hey, Joe, I got a coat for you.
Do you know Terry Malloy?
No, I don't. Never heard of him.
You're Terry Malloy, aren't you?
So what?
Didn't I see you fight a couple of years ago?
Without the birdseed, what do you want?
Identification.
Waterfront Crime Commission. What's that?
I just want to ask you a few questions.
We'll hold public hearings on waterfront crime...
and underworld infiltration of longshore unions.
-I don't know nothing. -You haven't heard the questions yet.
-What did you say? -You heard me.
There's a rumour that you're one of the last people to see Joey Doyle alive.
I don't know nothing.
Nobody's accusing you of anything, Mr. Malloy.
I hope you understand that.
Just want to ask you some questions about some people you may know.
-People I may know. -That's right.
-You better get out of here, buster! -Slow down, boy.
I don't know nothing, I ain't seen nothing, and I'm not saying nothing.
Why don't you and your girlfriend take off.
All right, Mr. Malloy!
You've every right not to talk if that's what you choose to do.
-The public has a right to know the facts. -Yeah.
We'll be seeing you again.
Never's going to be too much soon for me, Shorty.
Take it easy.
How do you like them mutts taking me for a pigeon.
-Who is it? -I don't know who they are.
You're three weeks behind on the last $25, but I'm willing to take a chance.
Some chance at ten percent a week and if we don't borrow, we don't work.
May you rot in hell, JP.
When I'm dead and gone, you'll know what a friend I was.
Why don't you drop dead now, so we can test your theory?
Condolences.
Hey, Pop, look.
Let her go, Tony.
I guess I spoke out of turn last night.
You think I'm just a gravy-train rider with a turned-around collar, don't you?
I see the sisters taught you not to lie.
All right. Loft gang: Malloy...
Hendriks, Padowski...
Westerfield, McGuier.
I've been thinking about your question, and you're right, Edie.
This is my parish.
I don't know how much I can do, but I'll never find out...
unless I come down here and take a good look for myself.
I need some extra banana carriers.
Bananas again.
I wonder when we'll get a boat from Ireland with good Irish whiskey on it.
Dugan, my boy, you're dreaming again.
All right. Kelly. Richie.
Yeah, you.
What's the matter? Nobody want to work today?
Who do you see to get a day's pay around here?
-Meatballs. -Definitely.
Come here.
Hey, Terry, grab that one!
Give me that.
Get away!
-Give it to me! -Why?
Give it to me!
What makes you so special?
Things are looking up on the dock.
Don't you recognise her? That's Joey Doyle's sister.
Give me that.
-You're Joey Doyle's sister? -Yes, I am.
You don't wanna go to work today anyhow.
It's been nice wrestling with you.
Edie!
Pop. Here's your tab, take it.
All right, give it to me. I can use it.
Now get back to the sisters where you belong.
I'm surprised at you, Father, if you don't mind my saying so.
Letting her see things ain't fit for the eyes of a decent girl.
All right, that's all. Come back tomorrow.
What do you do now?
Like Big Mac said, come back tomorrow.
Tomorrow? No ship tomorrow.
I've been standing here for five straight mornings and that bum there...
-Come on, get out of here! -looks right through you.
-I'm sorry, Father, I didn't mean it. -What do you want to do?
Come on, let's go get a ball.
Wait a minute. Is this all you do, just take it like this?
What about your unions?
No other union in the country'd stand for a thing like that.
The waterfront is tougher, Father, like it ain't part of America.
-Do you know how a trigger local works? -No. How?
You get up in the meeting, you make a motion,
the lights go out, then you go out.
That's how it's been since Johnny and his cowboys took over the local.
Name one place where it's safe to talk without getting clobbered.
-The church. -What?
The bottom of the church.
You know what you're letting yourself in for?
You got a cigarette on you?
Right over there.
-You working hard? -Yeah.
You wouldn't mind working once in a while to justify this lofty position, would you?
I finished the work. I counted all them bags.
We have an extra detail for you.
That's if you don't mind being disturbed or anything.
The priest and this Doyle girl are getting a meeting up together down at the church.
We want a rundown on the names and the numbers of all the players.
Wait a minute. All right, you're nominated.
Why me, Charley? I feel funny going down there.
I'd just be stooling for you.
Let me tell you what stooling is. Stooling is when you rat on your friend...
the guys you're with. Johnny wants a favour.
Don't think about it. Do it.
Go on. Join the congregation.
I thought there would be more of you here, but....
The Romans found out what a handful could do if it's the right handful.
I'm just a potato-eater, but isn't it simple as one, two, three?
One. The working conditions are bad.
Two. They're bad because the mob does the hiring.
Three. The only way to break the mob is to stop letting them get away with murder.
If one of you'll answer one question, we'd have a very good start.
And that question is: Who killed Joey Doyle?
Not one of you has a line on who killed Joey Doyle?
I have a hunch all of you could tell us something about it.
All right, then answer this one:
How can we call ourselves Christians and protect these murderers with our silence?
Jimmy Collins, you were Joey's best friend.
How can you just sit there and not say anything?
I'll always think of him as my best friend, but what do you want me to--
Who asked him in here?
I'm trying to find out what happened to Joey Doyle.
-Maybe you can be helpful. -Helpful?
The brother of Charley the Gent?
They'll help us get to the bottom of the river.
You better leave Charley out of this.
-You don't think he'd be helpful? -Why don't you ask him yourself?
-Maybe I will one of these days. -One of these days.
Now, listen, you know who the pistols are.
Are you going to keep still until they cut you down one by one?
Are you?
Dugan! How about you? Are you?
One thing you have to understand, Father, on the dock...
we've always been D and D.
-D and D? What's that? -Deaf and dumb.
No matter how much we hate the torpedoes, we don't rat.
Rat? Now boys, get smart.
I know you're getting pushed around, but there's one thing...
we have in this country, and that's ways of fighting back.
Getting the facts to the public.
Testifying for what is right against what is wrong.
What's ratting to them is telling the truth for you, can't you see that?
Can't you see that?
It seems to me we've gone just about as far as we can at this time.
I think you'll agree with that, Father.
So, I'd like to close with a few words from St. Matthew:
"Come unto me all you--"
What did I tell you about sticking your neck out.
This is a police problem, not ours.
These people need help.
Okay. Only don't blame me when they ship you off to Abyssinia.
I won't.
You better go home in pairs. Twos is two, you know.
Come on.
Pop!
Edie!
What's happened to Pop?
He's all right. He's an old man, they won't hurt him.
Get out, you!
Are you all right?
Yeah, considering they were using my head for a baseball.
You still D and D? Do you still call it ratting?
-Are you on the level? -What do you think?
If I stick my neck out and it's chopped off, is that the end?
-Or will you go all the way? -Down the line.
They'll put muscle on you, too, turned-around collar or not.
Wipe your face. Listen, you stand up and I'll stand up with you.
-Right down the wire? -So help me God.
I think we're okay.
Steel pipes and baseball bats.
They play pretty rough around here.
I can make it home now all right.
Which side are you with?
Me? I'm with me, Terry.
You got a dime for a cup of coffee?
Go on, beat it, will you?
A little dime you don't need?
I know you. You're Edie Doyle.
Come on. Beat it.
Your brother was a saint, the only one who ever tried to get me compensation.
You remember, Terry.
You was there that night.
Here's some change. Go have yourself a ball.
You don't buy me. You're still a bum.
So long, Edie.
Lord have mercy on Joey.
Who's calling me a bum?
Everybody loved Joey.
From little kids to the old rummies.
Did you know him very well?
You know, he got around.
What did that man mean just now?
Don't pay no attention to him. He's drunk, he's falling down. Everything.
He's a juicehead that hangs around the neighbourhood.
Don't pay no attention.
I better go now.
You don't have to be afraid of me. I'm not going to bite you.
I guess they don't let you walk with fellas where you've been?
You know how the sisters are.
Yeah.
-Are you training to be a nun? -lt's just a regular college.
It's run by the Sisters of St. Anne.
Where is that?
In Tarrytown.
-Where's that? -ln the country.
I don't like the country. The crickets make me nervous.
How often do you get in here?
I haven't been here since last Christmas.
We were going to have a Thanksgiving party.
That's nice.
What do you do up there? Just study?
I want to be a teacher.
Teacher? That's very good.
Personally, I admire brains.
My brother Charley is a very brainy guy. He had a couple of years of college.
It isn't just brains. It's how you use them.
Yeah, I get your thought.
You know, I've seen you a lot of times before.
Do you remember parochial school out on Puluski Street?
Seven, eight years ago?
-Your hair, you had your hair.... -Braids.
Looked like a hunk of rope.
You had wires on your teeth and glasses. Everything.
You was really a mess.
I can get home all right now, thanks.
Don't get sore. I was just kidding you a little bit.
I just mean to tell you that you're, you grew up very nice.
Thanks.
You don't remember me, do you?
I remembered you the first moment I saw you.
By the nose, huh?
Some people just got faces that stick in your mind.
I remember you were in trouble all the time.
Now you got me.
The way those sisters used to whack me, I don't know what.
They thought they was going to beat an education into me, but I foxed them.
Maybe they just didn't know how to handle you.
How would you have done it?
With a little more patience and kindness.
That's what makes people mean and difficult.
People don't care enough about them.
Are you kidding me?
I'd better get you home.
There's too many guys around here with only one thing on their mind.
Am I going to see you again?
What for?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Come on.
You're all packed. Here's your bus ticket and you're on your way back to St. Anne's.
I'm not ready to go back yet, Pop.
Edie, for years your mom and me put quarters in the cookie jar...
to keep you up there with the sisters...
and keep you from things like I've just seen outside the window.
A daughter of mine walking arm in arm with Terry Malloy.
-Do you know who Terry Malloy is? -Who is he, Pop?
He's the kid brother of Charley the Gent...
who is Johnny Friendly's right hand and a butcher in a camel hair coat.
Are you trying to tell me Terry is, too?
He tries to act tough...
but there's a look in his eye.
Yeah, a look in his eye. Hold your hats, brothers, here we go again.
You think he's one of them cases you're always dragging into the house...
and feeling sorry for...
like that litter of kittens you brought in.
The only one you wanted to keep had six toes and was cockeyed to boot.
Look at him. The little bum.
He said he wants to see me again.
See this arm?
Two inches longer than the other.
That's from years of working and sweating, lifting and swinging a hook.
Every time I heist a box or a coffee bag, I says to myself...
that is for Edie so she can be a teacher or something decent.
I promised your mom, Edie. Don't let her down.
I don't want you to think I'm not grateful for everything you've done.
For giving me the education and keeping me away from all this.
But I've seen things that I know are so wrong.
How can I go back to school and keep my mind on things that are just in books...
that aren't people living?
I'm going to stay.
I'm going to keep on trying to find out who is guilty for Joey.
What are you doing up there on the roof?
Just looking.
Take a look at the champion flock of the neighbourhood.
Fly pretty nice, huh?
Golden Warriors?
Yeah. I founded the Golden Warriors.
Might say that I was the original Golden Warrior.
This bum here is my shadow.
He thinks I'm a tough man because I boxed pro a lot.
Joey used to raise pigeons.
Yeah, he had a few birds.
I've been taking care of them.
I wouldn't have thought you'd be so interested in pigeons.
I just go for it.
You know this city is full of hawks?
That's a fact. They hang around on top of the big hotels.
They spot a pigeon in the park, right down on them.
You got a second?
I want to show you something.
What do you think of that fellow?
She's a beauty.
She's a he. His name is Swifty.
Look what he went and did.
He's my lead bird. He's always on top of the perch. If another bum tries...
to come along and take his place, he really lets him have it.
Even pigeons aren't peaceful.
There's one thing about them, they're very faithful.
They get married just like people.
Better.
They stay that way until one of them dies.
That's nice.
Go ahead. Fix the roof.
You want that egg?
Thanks.
Do you like beer?
I don't know.
I bet you never had a glass of beer.
-Did you ever have a glass of beer? -No.
You want to have one with me?
In a saloon?
I know a nice dump down here that has a special entrance for ladies.
Come on, it won't hurt.
Come on.
Okay.
Hey, you, mac.
Two Glockenheimers and two for chasers.
-Did you see the fight last night? -No.
A kid named Riley, both hands. Like you used to do.
I hope he got better dice than me.
Were you really a prizefighter?
I used to be.
How did you get interested in that?
I don't know. I had to scrap all my life, I might as well get paid for it.
When I was a kid my old man got bumped off.
Never mind how. Then they stuck Charley and me...
in a dump they call a "children's home."
Boy, that was some home.
Anyhow, I ran away from there and fought in the club smokers...
and peddled papers and Johnny Friendly bought a piece of me.
Bought a piece of you?
Yes. Then...
I was going pretty good there for awhile.
And after that....
What do you really care, am I right?
Shouldn't everybody care about everybody else?
Boy, what a fruitcake you are.
I mean, isn't everybody a part of everybody else?
And you really believe that drool?
Yes, I do.
Here we are. One for the lady and for the gent.
Here's to the first one, I hope it ain't the last.
Go ahead.
No, not like that. One hum.
Do you want to hear my philosophy of life?
Do it to him before he does it to you.
I never met anyone like you.
There's not a spark of sentiment, or romance...
or human kindness in your whole body.
What good does it to you besides get you in trouble?
And when things and people get in your way, you just knock them aside...
get rid of them. Is that your idea?
Don't look at me when you say that. It wasn't my fault what happened to Joey.
Fixing him wasn't my idea.
Who said it was?
Everybody's putting the needle on me.
You and the mugs in the church and Father Barry.
I didn't like the way he was looking at me.
He was looking at everybody the same way.
Oh, yeah?
What's with this Father Barry?
-What's his racket? -His racket?
Yeah, his racket.
-Everybody's got a racket. -But he's a priest.
Are you kidding, so what?
-That don't make no difference. -You don't believe anybody, do you?
Down here it's every man for himself.
It's keeping alive. It's standing with the right people so you get...
a little bit of change in your pocket.
-And if you don't? -lf you don't? Right down.
It's living like an animal.
I'd rather live like an animal than end up like....
Like Joey?
-Are you afraid to mention his name? -No.
Why do you keep harping on that for?
Come on, drink up. You got to get a little fun out of life.
Come on. I'll stick some music on.
What's the matter?
What's the matter with you?
Help me if you can for God's sake.
Edie, I'd like to help.
I'd like to help, but there's nothing I can do.
All right.
I shouldn't have asked you.
Edie, come on. Have a little beer.
Come on.
I don't want it.
You just stay here and finish your drink.
Don't go. I've got my whole life to drink.
Are you sore at me?
What for?
I don't know, for not being no help to you.
You would if you could.
Here I come.
Pick a winner.
First I got to kiss the bride.
Go on, you've kissed her before!
You can get out that way. You want me to take you?
-Come on. What's going on here? -Give me a cigarette.
You've got to stop smoking so much.
Come on, we'll get out through here.
What's the matter?
Come on.
That's a pretty tune.
Here's a stick of gum. It'll do you good.
-Thank you. -Do you like that music?
If I had my tuxedo, I'd ask you to dance, but....
Come on. You want to spin?
Come on, don't be afraid.
You dance divinely.
I think we're doing pretty good.
The sisters ought to see you now.
Wait a minute.
I feel like I'm just floating.
I'm just floating.
Just floating.
I been looking all over for you, Terry. The boss wants you.
Right now?
Yeah, he just got a call from "Mr. Upstairs."
Something's gone wrong. He's plenty hot.
I'm going to take her home first.
I wouldn't do that. I'll see the little lady home.
Tell him I'll come over there when I'm ready.
Hey, wait up!
Who was that?
I don't know. Some mug.
Who was he?
You got to quit trying to find out about Joey. It ain't safe.
I'm telling you it ain't safe.
Mr. Malloy, I was hoping I might find you here.
Excuse me, Miss.
You're being served with a subpoena, Mr. Malloy.
What?
Be at the State House, Courtroom 9, 10:00 Friday morning.
I told you I don't know nothing about that.
You can bring a lawyer if you wish.
You're privileged under the constitution to protect yourself...
against questions which might implicate you in any crimes.
You know what they're asking me to do?
All we want you to do, Mr. Malloy, is tell the truth.
Goodnight, kid. Nice wedding.
What are you going to do?
I ain't going to eat cheese for no cop and that's for sure.
It was Johnny Friendly who had Joey killed, wasn't it?
He had him killed or he had something to do with it, didn't he?
He and your big brother Charley?
You can't tell me, can you, because you're a part of it.
Because you're just as bad as the worst of them. Tell me the truth.
You better go back to that school out in daisyland.
You're driving yourself nuts, you're driving me nuts.
Quit worrying about the truth all the time. Worry about yourself.
I should've known you wouldn't tell me.
Pop said Johnny Friendly used to own you. I think he still owns you.
No wonder everybody calls you a bum.
Don't say that to me, Edie, don't say that to me now.
No wonder.
I'm only trying to help you out.
I'm trying to keep you from getting hurt. What more do you want me to do?
-Much more. -Wait a minute.
Much, much, much more.
Where are you going?
Hi there, Johnny, I was just coming over there.
-Where were you, in Chicago? -No, I was just on my way over there.
How many times you been knocked out, Terry?
Knocked out? Two times.
That's once too often.
Your brains must be rattling. What you got up there, Chinese bells?
I thought you were gonna keep an eye on that church meeting.
I was there. Nothing was happening.
Nothing happening! Some operator you got yourself there.
One more like him, we'd all be wearing striped pyjamas.
I'm telling you, Johnny, it was a big nothing. The priest did all the talking.
Half an hour later, a certain Timothy J. Dugan had a secret session...
with the crime commission, and he done all the talking.
Dugan, what does he know?
Just 39 pages of our operation, that's all.
Where'd you get that?
-I got it. -The complete works of Timothy J. Dugan.
I knew he had the guts, but I never--
Guts! Why, that crummy pigeon. He ought to have his neck wrung!
That's what we get for mixing with this punch-drunk brother of yours.
He was good for laughs, but this is business.
I don't like anyone goofing off in my business.
-I wasn't... -Why are you going around with his sister?
Just shut up!
It's just the Doyle broad, she's got him so he doesn't...
know where his feet is anymore.
It's an unhealthy relationship.
-Definitely! -Get rid of her...
unless you're both tired of living.
-You got her address? -Yeah.
We've got to do something to muzzle Dugan...
or he'll raise the biggest stink this town's ever seen.
We got the best muscle on the waterfront.
The time to use it is now. Pronto, if not sooner.
You know where you're going? Back in the hold. No more cushy job in the loft.
It's down in the hold with the sweat gang till you learn your lesson.
Let's go.
Wise up!
Come on, you're all right. Let's do it.
At last an Irish shipment.
And loaded to the gunnels with fine Irish whiskey.
You see, Kayo, the good Lord takes care of us all the time.
-That he does. -Come on out, Kayo, get it up.
All right, take it up. Take it away.
And don't go walking off with any of that!
You know how the boss feels about individual pilferage.
All right, all right.
Now you see the advantage of a little man in a big coat.
-Let me see you a minute afterwards. -What're you here for?
To see that we don't steal any of Mr. Friendly's precious cargo?
-I want to talk to you. -Get away from me, will you?
All right. Take it up. Take it away.
Kayo, you're a walking distillery.
Watch it!
Get a doctor!
He don't need a doctor. He needs a priest.
I came down here to keep a promise.
I gave Kayo my word that if he stood up to the Mob...
I'd stand up with him all the way.
And now Kayo Dugan is dead.
He was one of those fellows who had the gift for standing up.
This time they fixed him.
They fixed him for good this time, unless it was an accident...
like Big Mac says.
Some people think the Crucifixion only took place on Calvary.
They better wise up.
Taking Joey Doyle's life to stop him from testifying is a crucifixion.
Dropping a sling on Kayo Dugan...
because he was ready to spill his guts tomorrow...
that's a crucifixion.
Every time the mob puts the crusher on a good man...
tries to stop him from doing his duty as a citizen, it's a crucifixion.
And anybody who sits around and lets it happen...
keeps silent about something he knows has happened, shares the guilt of it...
just as much as the Roman soldier...
who pierced the flesh of Our Lord to see if He was dead.
Go back to your church, Father.
Boys, this is my church.
If you don't think Christ is down here on the waterfront...
you've got another guess coming!
Get off this dock, Father!
Tillio, don't do that.
-Whose side are you on, boy? -Let him finish.
Every morning...
when the hiring boss blows his whistle...
Jesus stands alongside you in the shape-up.
He sees why some of you get picked and some of you get passed over.
He sees the family men worrying about getting their rent...
and getting food for the wife and kids.
He sees you selling your souls to the mob for a day's pay.
The next bum that throws something deals with me!
I don't care if he's twice my size!
What does Christ think of the easy-money boys...
who do none of the work and take all the gravy?
How does he feel about the fellows who wear $150 suits...
and diamond rings on your union dues and your kickback money?
And how does He, who spoke up without fear against every evil...
feel about your silence?
Shut up about that!
Just watch this.
You see that?
You want to know what's wrong with our waterfront?
It's the love of a lousy buck. It's making love of a buck, the cushy job...
more important than the love of man.
It's forgetting that every fellow down here is your brother in Christ.
But remember, Christ is always with you.
Christ's in the shape-up, in the hatch, in the union hall.
He's kneeling right here beside Dugan and He's saying with all of you:
"If you do it to the least of mine, you do it to me."
What they did to Joey and to Dugan...
they're doing to you and you.
All of you!
And only you, only you with God's help...
have the power to knock them out for good.
Okay, Kayo.
Amen.
All right. Come on. Let's go. Break it up. Let's go to work.
Edie, here's Joey's jacket. I'm sure Kayo would wish you to have it back.
I brought you Joey's jacket.
Yours is coming apart.
Pigeons.
They're nervous.
There was a hawk around here before.
Father, I want to speak to you a minute.
Remember what you said about...
Kayo Dugan and keeping your mouth shut when you know the score.
I don't want to hear your confession.
I'll dig it out for myself and use it where it'll do the most good.
-Father Gregory will hear you. -I don't want to talk....
Wait a second, wait a minute.
I just want to talk to you one second.
You've got to listen to me.
I'm the one that set Joey Doyle up for the knock off.
Come on, take a walk with me, kid, and give it to me straight.
There's nothing I haven't heard. Come on.
It started out as a favour.
Favour, who am I kidding? It's "do it or else."
Believe me when I tell you I just thought they were...
going to lean on him a bit. I never thought he'd get knocked off.
I tried to tell Edie the other night.
I really tried to, I wanted to tell her.
She's the first nice thing that's ever happened to me.
What are you going to do about it?
What do you mean? About telling her?
Yes, about telling her. The commission. Your subpoena.
I know you got a subpoena.
I don't know.
It's like carrying a monkey around on your back.
It's a question of "who rides who."
If I spill, my life ain't worth a nickel.
And how much is your soul worth if you don't?
They're asking me to put the finger on my own brother.
Johnny Friendly used to take me to ball games when I was a kid.
Don't break my heart.
I wouldn't care if he gave you a life pass to the polo grounds.
So you've got a brother. Let me tell you something...
you've got other brothers getting the short hand...
while Johnny is getting mustard on his face at the polo grounds.
Ball games.
Listen, if I were you, I would walk right....
Never mind.
I'm not asking you to do anything, your own conscience has to do the asking.
Conscience.
-That stuff can drive you nuts. -Good luck.
Is that all you've got to say?
Come here.
Edie called me this morning.
She's coming here to talk to me.
Come on, why don't you tell her?
No curves.
Okay.
Thanks.
-You? -Honest to God, Edie....
Believe me, I swear to God, Edie....
Terry, guess who's here?
That joker from the crime commissioner's office.
Suppose I knew a guy that knocked somebody off...
you think I ought to turn him in?
You mean call a cop? Are you kidding?
You don't think I ought to turn him in?
You was a Golden Warrior once.
That's right.
You started the gang.
You looking for me?
No, not exactly. I was just resting my dogs a minute.
On the next investigation we get, I hope it's got buildings with elevators in them.
So far this one's just been climbing stairs.
What do you climb them for?
It's worth it if we can tell the waterfront story...
the way the people have a right to hear it.
Don't you think?
Didn't I see you in the Garden three or four years ago...
with a fellow named Wilson?
I thought you were going to take him that night.
Man, he really dumped you.
He dumped me?
What would you say if I told you I held that bum up for half a round?
I could see he was hurt.
What did you think I was doing with them combinations, petting him?
You just couldn't finish him off?
Don't monkey around there.
Why didn't you finish him off?
-I was doing a favour for some pals. -Favour?
That's the way it was.
If I'd have put him down, I'd have had a title shot.
I was ready that night.
You sure looked it. That's when I figured it was all over.
It was all over, except for the lousy bet!
-My own. -Yeah.
I guess I'd better get going.
Hit those stairs again.
Was that a hook or an uppercut you caught him with that first time?
I didn't use no hooks. I was strictly a short puncher.
It looked like a hook to me.
I had that bum all figured out. He had a good left hand.
I let him tag me with the left hand for a couple of rounds...
so just when he starts, he thinks he's getting cute, I step inside a jab...
with a left, with a right, with a left.
I had him in my arms and from there on in we were just dancing.
And that's a fact!
When those guys want to win a bet, there's nothing they won't stop at.
I didn't hear them, boss...
but I seen them nose to nose, like pair of lovers.
The flatfoot was eating it up.
So they've been seen together and he smiled at her.
That doesn't mean he's going to talk.
There is no evidence until he gives public testimony.
Thanks for the legal advice, Charley.
That's what we kept you around here for.
How do we keep him from giving this testimony?
Ain't that what you call "the main order of business"?
He's a good kid.
-You know that. -He's a bum.
After all the days I gave him in the loft, he's got no gratitude.
Shut up!
I'm conducting this investigation.
This girl and the father, they got their hooks...
in the kid so deep he doesn't even know which end is up any more.
I ain't interested in his mental condition.
All I want to know is: is he D and D or is he a canary?
-I wish I knew. -So do l, Charley.
For your sake.
What do you want me to do?
It's simple. Drive him out to this place we've been using...
try to straighten him out on the way. If you don't, give him to Gerry G.
You can't do that.
Maybe the boy is out of line, but he's just a confused kid!
Confused kid!
First he crosses me in public and gets away with it...
then the next joker, pretty soon I'm just another fellow around here!
Johnny, I can't do that.
Then don't.
-Who do you like in the third? -lt's got to be New Hope.
Definitely.
Johnny...
it's my kid brother.
That's for you to figure out.
You can have it your way or you can have it his way...
but you can't have it both ways. Am I right, Truck?
Definitely.
Okay, on your horse...
deep thinker.
Hi, Charley.
I'm glad you stopped by for me. I've been wanting to talk to you.
-Sure, kid. -Where to?
Go to River St. I'll tell you where to stop.
I thought we was going to the Garden?
We are, but I want to cover a bet on the way over.
Besides, this'll give us a chance to talk.
Nobody ever stopped you from talking, Charley.
The grapevine says that you got a subpoena.
The guys know you're not a cheese-eater.
They think you shouldn't be on the outside so much...
but a little on the inside. I have a few things for you at the docks.
A steady job...
a couple extra potatoes, that's all I want.
That's great when you're a kid, but...
you're getting on, you're pushing 30, slugger.
You know it's time to think about getting some ambition.
I always figured I'd live a little bit longer without it.
Maybe.
There's a boss loader slot that's open on the new pier we're opening up.
It pays six cents on every...
100 pounds that goes in and every 100 pounds that goes out...
and you don't have to lift a finger.
That's $200, $300, $400 a week.
$400 a week just for the openers.
I get all that dough for not doing nothing?
You don't do anything and you don't say anything.
You understand?
There's more to this than I thought, Charley.
I'm telling you there's a lot more.
You're not thinking of testifying against some people that we might know?
I don't know, Charley.
That's what I want to talk to you about.
Do you know how much the piers are worth that we control through the local?
Do you think Johnny's going to jeopardise the whole set-up...
for one rubber-lipped, ex-tanker who's walking on his heels? What the....
I could've been a lot better.
The point is we don't have much time!
I'm telling you, I haven't made up my mind yet!
Make up your mind before we get to 437 River St!
Before we get to where, Charley?
Listen, Terry. Take the job, no questions. Take it!
Terry, take this job, please.
Look, kid....
How much do you weigh, slugger?
When you weighed 168 pounds...
you were beautiful.
You could have been another Billy Conn.
That skunk we got you for a manager...
he brought you along too fast.
It wasn't him, Charley. It was you.
Remember that night in the Garden?
You came down to my dressing room and said, "Kid, this ain't your night.
"We're going for the price on Wilson."
You remember that?
"This ain't your night."
My night! I could have taken Wilson apart!
So what happens, he gets the title shot outdoors in the ball park...
and what do I get? A one-way ticket to Palookaville!
You was my brother, Charley.
You should have looked out for me a little bit.
You should've taken care of me a little so I wouldn't...
have to take dives for short-end money.
I had some bets down for you. You saw some money.
You don't understand, I could have had class!
I could have been a contender.
I could have been somebody.
Instead of a bum...
which is what I am. Let's face it.
It was you, Charley!
Okay.
I'll tell them...
I couldn't find you.
Ten to one they won't believe me.
Here, you take this.
You're going to need it.
You, pull over.
Take me to the Garden.
Stay away from me!
Edie?
Come on, open the door, please!
Stop it!
I want you to stay away from me.
I know what you want me to do but I ain't doing it, so forget it.
I don't want you to do anything.
You let your conscience tell you what to do.
Shut up about that conscience, that's all I've been hearing!
I never mentioned the word before. You just stay away from me!
Edie, you love me.
I didn't say I didn't love you, I said stay away from me!
-I want you to stay with me. -Stay away from me!
Terry!
Terry, your brother's down here! He wants to see you!
Charley?
Your brother's down here.
Come on down here.
He wants to see you.
Come on down!
-What is it Terry? -Charley, he's in trouble.
Be careful.
Charley!
Terry?
Terry! Your brother's down here!
Do you hear what I hear?
Terry!
That's the same way they called Andy, the night I lost him.
Edie, be careful! Edie, be careful!
They got Charley.
Terry, I'm frightened. Let's get out of here, please.
First Joey, then Dugan, and now Charley, and next....
Please, Terry, some place where we can live in peace.
I'm going to take it out of their skulls.
Charley...
Terry, they'll kill you, too.
Go get the father. Tell him to take care of Charley.
And then come back here and stay with him till he gets here.
Terry, please don't do anything, please!
For God's sake, don't leave him alone here long!
-Please, Terry. -Do what I tell you.
-Where's John Friendly? -He's not here now.
Give me a shot.
Take it easy.
Don't give me no advice, give me the shot.
Why don't you go home before Big John gets here?
Just give me a whiskey.
Stick around, Tillio.
There, sit down.
Get out of that phone booth!
Stay where you are!
I want to see you, Terry.
I'm right in front of you.
Don't give me a hard time, Terry.
What do you want?
Your gun.
Go and chase yourself.
Give me the gun.
You go to hell.
-What did you say? -Go to hell.
-Sorry, let me help you up. -Get your hands off me!
Now what am I going to do?
You want to be a brave man by firing lead into another man?
-lt's none of your business! -That's being brave!
Mind your own business!
Shooting a man isn't being brave!
It's none of your business!
Do you want to hurt Johnny Friendly?
Do you want to fix him?
-Do you really want to finish him? -What do you think?
For what he did to Charley and a dozen other men?
Don't fight him like a hoodlum down here in the jungle. That's what he wants.
He'll hit you in the head and plead self-defence.
You'll fight him in the courtroom tomorrow with the truth.
As you know the truth.
Now you get rid of that gun.
Unless you haven't the guts, and if you haven't, hold onto it!
Give me a beer.
Do you want a beer? Make it two.
You mean to sit there and tell me that your local takes in...
$65,500 every year...
and keeps no financial records?
Sure. We got records.
Where are they?
We was robbed last night, and we can't find no books.
-You know you're under oath? -Sure.
Isn't it odd to you that five different waterfront locals...
were broken into last night?
And the only item missing from all of them was the financial records?
What do you mean, odd? Like I told you, we was robbed.
That's all for now.
Call the next witness.
Before you call the next witness...
are all the officers of Local 374 present this morning?
Will the following please rise as their names are called?
Mr. Michael J. Skelly, also known as Johnny Friendly, President.
Mr. Lewis O. Janotta, Vice President.
Mr. Daniel D. Coogan, Financial Secretary.
Mr. Mladen Sokolivitch, Delegate.
Mr. Tillio A. Rodelli, Delegate.
Recording Secretary.
Thank you, gentlemen.
-Next witness. -Mr. Malloy.
Raise your right hand.
-Name, please. -Terry Malloy.
Swear to tell the truth, the whole truth, and only the truth?
-Right. -I do.
-I do. -Be seated, please.
Mr. Malloy...
is it true that the night Joey Doyle was found dead...
you were the last one to see him before he was pushed from the roof?
Yes.
Is it true you went immediately--
Wait! Except for the guys that pushed him off.
Is it true you went immediately to the Friendly bar...
and expressed your feelings about the murder to Mr. Johnny Friendly?
John Friendly, right.
Mr. Malloy...
can you tell me whether Mr. Friendly, or I should say, Mr. Skelly...
said anything to you to indicate his responsibility in getting rid of Joey Doyle?
Right.
Would you say that Mr. Friendly made it clear to you...
it was absolutely necessary he murder Joey Doyle in order...
to maintain his control...
on the docks of the waterfront localsl Is that correct?
Will there be anything else?
Yes, Sidney, if Mr. Friendly calls, I'm out.
-Anytime today? -lf he calls ever, I'm out!
Very well.
Thank you, Mr. Malloy.
You've done more than break the Joey Doyle case.
We've begun to make it possible for honest men to work the docks...
with job security and peace of mind.
You may step down. That's all for now.
Mr. Michael J. Skelly, please.
You just dug your own grave. Go fall in it.
You're dead on this waterfront and every waterfront...
from Boston to New Orleans.
You don't drive a truck or a cab...
you don't push a baggage rack you don't work no place, you're dead!
Will you quit following me? Why don't you get off my tail?
Orders. You're hot. You ought to be glad we're following you.
You're making me feel like a canary.
-Well.... -Lay off.
Hi, Cheeky.
Who's your friend?
I made some hot coffee. I thought you might want some.
Anyway, it's all over.
My friends don't want to talk to me.
Are you sure they're your friends?
I'll see you later.
Hey, champ, how's the kid.
What's with him?
A pigeon for a pigeon!
Terry.
The kid.
Tommy?
What did he have to do that for?
Every one of them.
Terry, there's no place that's safe for you now on the waterfront.
Maybe inland...
out west some place...
a farm.
A farm?
You could do anything, as long as you're away from Johnny Friendly.
You tried to help the longshoremen...
and they just turn their backs and stick to their stupid D and D!
Are they taking chances for you? Why should you?
You're not even listening to me, are you?
You're going down there.
Just because Johnny Friendly warned you not to, you're going down there.
You think you got to prove that you're not afraid of them!
Well, go ahead, get it over with.
Go down and get yourself killed you stupid, pigheaded....
What are you trying to prove?
They always said I was a bum.
Well, I ain't a bum, Edie.
Don't worry, I'm not going to hurt nobody.
I'm just going to go down there...
and get my rights.
Everybody works today!
Wolfgang.
Hendricks.
Padowski.
Martin.
Dalton.
Wurthy.
Hauffman.
-What do you think? -That ain't such a bad picture of you, boss.
Stop breathing that clam sauce on me.
I wish you'd let me go to work on that cheese-eater.
I'd top the bum off lovely.
Wait'll we get off this front page.
Then he's mine.
I want him.
You hear that? He's mine.
Where are them cops of yours, stoolie? You're going to need them.
You're still short in the hatch, Mac.
Spec. Bring me the first man you see.
You.
Here's your man.
You want more of the same? Come back tomorrow.
All right, that's it.
I hope that bum comes down here. I'd love if he comes down here.
Did you ever hear of the Sullivan Law?
They'll be down on us for the slightest infraction now, anything.
I'm going to be indicted any minute!
Come on, gimme.
Will you get it through your heads...
they're dusting off the hot seat for me!
We're a law-abiding union.
Understand?
Friendly!
John Friendly, come out of there!
You want to know the trouble with you?
You think it makes you a big man if you give the answers.
At the right time I'll catch up with you. Think about that.
-Now, go on, beat it. Don't push your luck. -Wait a minute.
You take them heaters away from you and you're nothing, you know that?
You'll talk yourself in the river!
You take the good goods away and the kickbacks...
and shakedown cabbage and the pistoleros and you're nothing!
Your guts is all in your wallet and your trigger finger!
You ratted on us, Terry!
From where you stand, maybe. But I'm standing over here now!
I was ratting on myself all them years, I didn't even know it.
You gave it to Joey, you gave it to Dugan...
and you gave it to Charley who was one of your own.
You think you're God Almighty, but you know what you are?
You're a cheap...
lousy, dirty, stinking mug...
and I'm glad what I done to you!
You hear that?
I'm glad what I done!
And I'm going to keep on doing it till I get--
Come on, come on.
That boy fights like he used to.
-They'll kill him. -lt's a massacre.
He's one of theirs anyway.
-What are we waiting for? -Let's go!
That's enough.
Just let him lay there.
What happened?
Jimmy, what happened?
Where are you going?
Let me by.
You want him?
You can have him!
The little rat's yours.
Get some fresh water!
Terry.
Who's in charge here?
Yours truly is in charge here.
We got to get this ship out of here. It's costing us money.
Blow your whistle.
All right you guys, get to work!
Come on!
-What goes? -I'll have them working in two minutes.
He better get these men to work.
Come on, you guys, on the double! Get to work!
Come on. Get in there. Get in there.
-How about Terry? -lf he don't work, we don't work.
Work! He can't even walk!
You want to know who works? The ones I pick to work.
Now get going. Come on all of you, get in there.
Come on, get out here.
Come on, Pop, on the double, you work today.
All my life you pushed me around.
Come on.
Come on, you walk in with them.
If Terry walks in, we walk in with him. They're waiting for him to walk in.
Did you hear that, Terry?
Terry, did you hear that?
Yeah.
You lost the battle, but you have a chance to win the war.
-What do I have to do? -Walk.
Can you walk?
-Walk. -Yes, walk.
To the pier, I mean.
-We'll walk in with you. -So the shippers can see...
we'll take no more orders from Johnny Friendly.
Then it'll give us back our union, so we can run it on the up and up.
Johnny Friendly's laying odds that you won't get up.
What are you standing around for? Come on, help me!
Come on, you guys.
Put me on my feet. Come on.
How you doing?
Am I on my feet?
You're on your feet.
-I don't think I'm gonna make it. -Terry!
You can.
Just finish what you started. You can.
Give me my hook.
Look, for God's sake, what're you trying to do?
Take your hands off him. Keep going.
Leave him alone!
All right, let's go to work!
Where you guys going? Wait a minute.
I'll remember this. I'll remember every one of you!
I'll be back! Don't you forget that!
I'll be back!